Guide to the New York Metro Area Postal Union Oral History OH.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
New York Metro Area Postal Union Oral History
1976-1978
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Schechter, Dana
Cornell University
OH.003
2 Linear Feet in 2 flat boxes and 1 letter manuscript box
68 audiocassettes
This collection consists of oral history interviews of 15 retired officers or activists of the New York Metro Area Postal Union, as well as interview transcripts. The interviews cover the topics of postal service working conditions, the evolution of the Union and its leadership, the Local 10, the National Federation of Post Office Clerks, the organization of Postal Union of Manhattan – Bronx Clerks, National Postal Clerks Union, and the national postal strike of 1970. The collection also contains an extensive interview with Morris Biller, President of the union from 1959-80, when he became president of the national union.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Dana Schechter on behalf of Cornell University in circa 1989. The accession number associated with this gift is 1980.021.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by the interviewee's last name.
Historical Note
The New York Area Postal Union represents over 21,000 postal clerks, motor vehicle operators, maintenance, and mail handlers in New York and New Jersey. The local resulted from the 1958 secession of officers and members of Local 10, National Federation of Post Office Clerks, an organization dating back to 1901. The secessionists favored an industrial organization that would include all postal crafts.
Barbara Wertheimer, labor educator at Cornell NYSSILR's New York Labor Extension, conceived of an oral history project utilizing union retiree groups to document workers' contributions to New York City. The study of the New York Metro Postal Workers began in 1976 with a small grant under the direction of Dana Schecter. For two years, Schecter met with a group of retired postal workers, trained them in oral history techniques, and set them to the task of the interviewing. Schecter donated the tapes and transcripts to the Wagner Archives in 1980.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Related Materials
For more materials related to the New York Metro Area Postal Union, see:
New York Metro Area Postal Union Collection Records (WAG.103),
Josie McMillian's oral history interview in the New Yorkers at Work Oral History Collection (OH.001).
Scope and Contents
Barbara Wertheimer, labor educator at Cornell NYSSILR's New York Labor Extension, conceived of an oral history project utilizing union retiree groups to document workers' contributions to New York City. The study of the New York Metro Postal Workers began in 1976 with a small grant under the direction of Dana Schecter. For two years, Schecter met with a group of retired postal workers, trained them in oral history techniques, and set them to the task of the interviewing. Schecter donated the tapes and transcripts to the Wagner Archives in 1980.
This collection consists of oral history interviews of 15 retired officers or activists of the New York Metro Area Postal Union, as well as transcripts of each of the interviews. The interviews cover the topics of postal service working conditions, the evolution of the Union and its leadership, the Local 10, the National Federation of Post Office Clerks, the organization of Postal Union of Manhattan – Bronx Clerks, National Postal Clerks Union, and the national postal strike of 1970. The collection also contains an extensive interview with Morris Biller, President of the union from 1959-80, when he became president of the national union.
All interviews have master recordings (stored in Box 2) and user access copies (stored in Box 3). All interviews have paper transcripts with the exception of Leo Goodwin and Otto Gottlieb.
Labor unions -- Organizing -- New York (N.Y.); United States Postal Service |x Employees |x History.; Postal Strike -- United States -- 1970.; Strikes and lockouts |x Postal service.; Labor union leaders -- Portraits.; Labor union members |z United States.; Oral history.; Schechter, Dana; Cornell University
- Biller, Morris, 1976-1978; cuid43959
  Scope and Contents
  Biller was President of New York Area Postal Union of the American Postal Workers, AFL-CIO, as well as Regional Coordinator for the Northeast Region of the American Workers' Postal Union.
  - Master recording, cuid43974 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_001)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Duration: 63 min
  - Master recording, cuid43975 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_002)
  - Master recording, cuid43976 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_003)
  - Master recording, cuid43977 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_004)
    Duration: 75 min
  - Master recording, cuid43978 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_005)
    Duration: 20 min; Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank.
  - Master recording, cuid43979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_006)
    Duration: 64 min
  - Master recording, cuid43980 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_007)
    Duration: 62 min
  - Master recording, cuid43981 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_008)
    Duration: 30 min; Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank.
  - Access copies (Box 3, Audiocassette 003_030, 003_031, 003_032, 003_033, 003_034, 003_035, 003_036, 003_037)
  - Transcripts (Box 1, Folder 1, 2, 3)
- Epstein, Max, November, 1976; cuid43960
  Epstein discusses work experiences, McCarthyism and the Union in the 1930s.
  - Master recording, cuid43982 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_009)
  - Master recording, cuid43983 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_010)
    Duration: 42 min
  - Access copies (Box 3, Audiocassette 003_038, 003_039)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Goldberg, Bernard, November 26, 1976; cuid43961
  Goldberg discusses finance insurance funds, substition work, and work inequities.
  - Master recording, cuid43984 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_011)
    Duration: 40 min
  - Access copies (Box 3, Audiocassette 003_040, 003_041)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Goodwin, Leo, November 30, 1976; cuid43962
  - Master recording, cuid43985 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_012)
    Duration: 23 min; Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank.
  - Access copy (Box 3, Audiocassette 003_042)
- Gottlieb, Otto, November 11, 1976; cuid43963
  - Master recording, cuid43986 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_013)
    Duration: 45 min
  - Access copy (Box 3, Audiocassette 003_043)
- Kamish, Harry, December 9, 1976; cuid43964
  Kamish was a delegate addressing poor working conditions; he discusses the Summerfield suspension and the 1958 break from AFL-CIO.
  - Master recording, cuid43987 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_014)
    Duration: 65 min
  - Access copy (Box 3, Audiocassette 003_044)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Kaye, Abraham, 1976-1977; cuid43965
  Kaye was a supervisor who was with the postal service from 1913-1958.
  - Master recording, cuid43988 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_015)
    Duration: 23 min; Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank
  - Master recording, cuid43989 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_016)
    Duration: 53 min
  - Access copies (Box 3, Audiocassette 003_047, 003_048)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Mandell, Sidney, January 15, 1977; cuid43966
  Mandell discusses being a woman on the job, GPO incoming mail, and general changes in the work environment.
  - Master recording, cuid43990 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_017)
    Duration: 60 min; Preservation Note: Poor audio quality on side 2 and 00:15:43 - 00:30:30 on side 1.
  - Access copies (Box 3, Audiocassette 003_045, 003_046)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Resnick, Elsie, November 26, 1976; cuid43967
  Elsie Resnick discusses sexism at work, working conditions, GPO incoming mail, Sick Aid, and the 1970 strike.
  - Access copy, cuid43991 (Box 3, Audiocassette 003_047)
    Duration: 52 min
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Resnick, Robert, November 26, 1976; cuid43968
  Robert Resnick discusses supervisor negligence, GPO incoming mail, and the 1970 strike.
  - Master recording, cuid43992 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_018)
    Duration 54 min
  - Access copies (Box 3, Audiocassette 003_048, 003_049, 003_050)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Rosner, Milton, April 27, 1977; cuid43969
  Rosner was Secretary-Treasurer of New York Metro Postal Workers; he discusses the credit union, politics and finances, and dangers of the job.
  - Master recording, cuid43993 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_019)
  - Master recording, cuid43994 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_020)
    Duration: 21 min; Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank.
  - Master recording, cuid43995 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_021)
    Duration: 93 min
  - Access copies (Box 3, Audiocassette 003_051, 003_052, 003_053, 003_054, 003_055, 003_056, 003_057, 003_058)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Ryland, Arthur, November, 1976; cuid43970
  Ryland discusses racism, the lengthy fight to be allowed to sit on the job, case stories, and the 1969 Contsitution Convention.
  - Master recording, cuid43996 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_022)
  - Master recording, cuid43997 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_023)
    Duration: 26 min; Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank.
  - Access copies (Box 3, Audiocassette 003_059, 003_060)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Salk, Charles, June 28, 1976; cuid43971
  Salk discusses early labor conditions, his rise to leadership, and Dave Edelson.
  - Master recording, cuid43998 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_024)
    Duration: 94 min
  - Access copies (Box 3, Audiocassette 003_061, 003_062)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Seligman, Philip, June 29, 1976; cuid43972
  This group interview discusses the break from AFL-CIO and the fight to enforce exams for managers, among other topics.
  - Master recording, cuid43999 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_025)
  - Access copies (Box 3, Audiocassette 003_063, 003_064)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Group Interview: Rosner, Ryland, Salk, 1977; cuid43973
  - Master recording, cuid44000 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_026)
    Duration: 3 min; Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank.
  - Master recording, cuid44001 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_027)
  - Master recording, cuid44002 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_028)
  - Master recording, cuid44003 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_029)
  - Access copies (Box 3, Audiocassette 003_065, 003_066, 003_067, 003_068)
  - Transcripts (Box 1, Folder 15, 16)